<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Open Integrity</title>
 <link href="http://openintegrity.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://openintegrity.github.io/"/>
 <updated>Sun, 29 May 2016 11:38:01 +0000</updated>
 <id>http://openintegrity.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jun Matsushita</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 <entry>
   <title>Impact Workshop at the IFF in Valencia</title>
   <link href="http://openintegrity.github.io/blog/2016-03-08-internet-freedom-festival.md"/>
   <updated>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</updated>
   <id>http://openintegrity.github.io</id>
   <content type="html">
Activists and technologists came together last month at the Internet Freedom Festival in Valencia, Spain. The Open Integrity Initiative (OII) team joined hundreds of like minded participants in discussing how to keep the Internet open and uncensored for a week of multidisciplinary collaboration.

&lt;!--more--&gt;

Our team held a workshop on Saturday the 5th March where participants contributed their thoughts and experiences about the type of issues faced by at-risk users such as activists, human rights defenders or journalists. We explored how weak and strong spots in software played a role in user security and privacy. What we learned contribute to the Open Integrity Initiative’s software assessment metrics. 

&lt;iframe src&#x3D;&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1sDApfSQ-1EnJbRcfJPxy0JBGjhkM06bjrkDuld7cdko/embed?start&#x3D;false&amp;amp;loop&#x3D;false&amp;amp;delayms&#x3D;3000&quot; frameborder&#x3D;&quot;0&quot; width&#x3D;&quot;640&quot; height&#x3D;&quot;480&quot; allowfullscreen&#x3D;&quot;true&quot; mozallowfullscreen&#x3D;&quot;true&quot; webkitallowfullscreen&#x3D;&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

After a quick presentation to introduce the project, the participants shared impact stories on software practices which can put the end-users at risk or help reduce it. They drew on hypothetical scenarios or real situations which helped highlight specific issues or good practices in a variety of contexts.

We&#x27;ve collected these stories as part of our impact framework and will make [them available in the impact section of our site](../../impact) where you will be able to further contribute to them.

Some interesting impact stories that emerged were for instance related to the hacking of a Google account made possible because the user was kept logged in during 30 days (even though two-factor authentication is activated). Another participants shared that Tibetan dissidents where affected by malware that benefited from Baidu Browser&#x27;s lack of secured and verified update mechanism. 

This brainstorming session benefited from the variety of backgrounds and experience of the participants and helped shaped our thinking around how to link the software assessment metrics to real world and documented impact stories. 

If you would like to know more about the workshop, you can access the IFF presentation. If you want to share your own impact stories related to a tool or software, feel free to drop us an email or tweet at @openintegrity.</content>
 </entry>
 <entry>
   <title>Booting up the Open Integrity Index</title>
   <link href="http://openintegrity.github.io/blog/2016-03-01-booting-up.md"/>
   <updated>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</updated>
   <id>http://openintegrity.github.io</id>
   <content type="html">
If you&#x27;ve been following the Open Integrity, you will have noticed that after [our initial efforts in 2013](https://wiki.openintegrity.org/doku.php?id&#x3D;workplan), the project has been on hold. During this first phase, we developed the foundations for [our criteria](https://wiki.openintegrity.org/doku.php?id&#x3D;criteria_subcriteria_claim) and setup [a beta platform](https://openintegrity.org/v1). We now advance with [new funders](../../about#funding-partners) to develop the next step of the project with us.

&lt;!--more--&gt;

In this first phase we set the tone of the initiative and the values that we adhere to:
 - **We care about the impact of technology on all users** and particularly those who depend on it to enjoy their fundamental rights.
 - **We take a holistic approach to understanding the impact of technology** which includes the technical features tools make available, but also their usability and the governance and policies of the tool makers.
 - **We believe that security by transparency** is the way to go, yet we know that there are also best practices to follow with closed source software that make a difference for users.

**Open Integrity Initiative** has assembled a list of a hundred possible metrics related to various aspects of software development, including governance, systems, architecture, build and user experience. In this [new phase](../../about#funding) we will shift our focus towards the **gathering of measurement and claims** and the **development of a knowledge framework** about the adoption of best practices that support the security and privacy of software.

Data about the adoption of security and privacy best practices are often difficult to find and rarely easy for users to understand. How can the adoption of these practices be measured, and what is the most useful structure for such a broad range of measurements? How can we answer **reliably and consistently** questions such as:
- Which tools are **open-source**?
- Which tools provide **end-to-end encryption**, implement **forward secrecy** or support **two-factor authentication**?
- Which have security features that are **usable without prior expertise or training**?
- Which can be **downloaded securely and verified** to be authentic?

This is what we&#x27;re setting out to answer. In the next 6 months we&#x27;ll focus on [developing partnerships](../../partners#measurement) in order to **define metrics and collect data** that will be available for an audience of professionals (software engineers, trainers, advocacy organizations) and will help provide answers about best practices adoption.
</content>
 </entry>

</feed>
